I'm here with Bruno and he's gone he's
got tons of stuff to get tons of stuff
check it out
how many subscribers you got 20,000
20,000 let's judge awesome unfriended me
Oh Mick Mike yep man okay show us Danny
this is an Arduino spot welder yep
so people building budgets the 18 650
batteries so they need a spot welder so
this connects to a micro battery yeah
and it's like super high current yeah so
this base we're not doing a controlling
so Garros Betsy's a nice Adam Dyer
before you know once you do the pulse
you need to cut it current it so it can
be a big thing so you need to kind of
like a dump it in here somewhere
we're the fridge yeah layers ilysm the
logic board alito LCD little control
here that's a nice compact form factor I
like it made in India brews and some
people don't like the idea but this is
the 8686 50 cell yeah somebody did you
just put end caps on this which is a
cell board and then you made a screw
terminal so yeah welding right so what
happening so you can just bolt it you
can remove and you keep good bunch like
a beauty
[Music]
yeah so here so you see a 1863 cell
right so normally have to spot weld or
soldering cells which is not good idea
but here you can just say like there's a
little spring thing with so you just go
here bang well that's just the direction
yeah it's just a very tight fit like
yeah it's not very like it's good
prototyping yeah but if you go like you
know like I do electric bikes electric
motorcycle this end up being really big
there's a lot of space between here but
for prototyping awesome for six you can
just build a serious parallel we just
screw nuts and stuff it's awesome
but else we got but is lead acid battery
here from 1930s 1930 1930s made in
England
it says here so made in England so this
I still got some crystals acid crystals
so they've just dried up probably yeah
this was probably sitting the Sun and
then what happened is it just dried out
because all things all the you know the
seal here is just gone so this plate
it's probably like if you put water back
inside here you might bring the acid
that you like maybe I need a grump I
engineer to come in 1930 it's pretty old
yeah I want to go back to this project
and see what happens so let's open here
Christo's
I think so I don't really understand
about acid to be honest because I'm more
lithium lithium cobaltite a manganese
stuff like yeah so this room is girl
grandpa technology I'm interested he Bay
Tasers alright so I've done I found the
most powerful oh I could again I bought
like 20 yeah and then I found this mod
your likes and I was like yeah you know
I'm gonna buy 20 old high voltage they
just sleek right so they just go the
shortest path so happening so I kind of
put them in parallel I want to put in
power
and I was like how could I put in
parallel because he needs to be you
can't just go like putting any
directions so it's just like I need to
make some insulation here yes but they
don't bleed and it is gonna be 30 amps
very obsessor 30 battery amps but this
is about 40 kilowatts kilo volts Oh
40,000 bullets so I'm a bit scared of
pumping 30 amps and something goes wrong
here does it like spark across at random
spots so I haven't experienced than in
experiments with this like this in Palo
okay yeah like this you might have some
sparks but they always fulfill the
shortest path of cause like a lightning
yep right so I'll do some experiments on
my curve in this way a curve in the
other way and see what bizarre result
okay here
yeah but I've done I put this thing
together months ago but I'm kind of like
I want to sum up with me when I'm the
experiments someone up something might
go wrong
yeah yes you wanna do this is from
master instruments Australia made in
Australia so this is Australian Army
multimeter use was used probably a
Vietnam War a record I don't know
yeah so look canvas so it's not
reflective yep right oh like the army
stuff can be reflective otherwise people
see you and this also it's actually
designed for field use yeah yeah right
you use the instructions all printing
aluminium course
yeah so it's it's gonna last
say hang on and then we go for my ribs
agent approves wait yeah yeah look the
style and what you see what's the
connector uh-huh
oh I can smell it in his mouth hold
smell oh yeah yeah and then this let me
get the red one it looks better in the
camera yep
hopefully it's not your dark so it's got
a little hook so that's the only one and
then though what one thing you might
like to see is Harley brake service I
think no I think it's I saw somewhere
the last calibration z mm it's a bit of
a stop here 1994 for this was the last
calibration 91 for yeah let me just open
here try to remove this thing so it's
missing one knob here yeah I tested the
voltage is fine still works
yeah then there's a funny battery here
yeah so these batteries would be weird
so but it's got a nice of gasket nice
gasket and see-through as well see this
silicon silicon grease yeah you know
like yeah yeah the dialectic thing yeah
so that of I think it's a pressure vent
I don't know they might something well I
don't know entirely waterproof yeah well
it's been a nice leg better than the
ones are we gonna feel China it ain't
here
yeah yeah well this is a fun training
yeah old school you know like my boss
awesome thanks Bruno righty
Sam
[Applause]
[Music]
yes for this night
yeah do you know a good home for this oh
yes from microscope it's an electron
microscope anyone who needs a good home
for it contact gap in 2500 electron
microscope 3 cows primates rebuilding
but no mechanics from the vacuum should
be fine please get in touch
it's into my storage unit I really want
to he wants to get rid of it so we what
a demonstration checkers yeah
[Applause]
because
we do the race will be on container for
another two months if you see sheet
machines oh I do actually
hello how many subscribers we got total
between these two at least a million
[Music]
odd way breadboard summer next
breadboard
what on earth is that
which one the bag of the skate bag okay
so like the skate or the time bomb
waiting to happen so that's that's not
gonna do well so we've got LED ice
skates basically an LED strip with an 18
650 battery holder is it tied to the
side we've got a larger one is for demo
purpose the next version yeah next
version will be inside the battery
holder of the skate hauler itself
ideally a smaller version scan to each
skate so it's much easier to print one
by the bolts into the side is glue it in
it won't fall out much even safer for
hockey players so you can actually wear
these on the ice hopefully but even then
for DIY skate idealized with do just go
skating all right hell of a lot of fun
it looks so mad on the ice then we've
got a heavy-duty armored backpack with a
bluetooth
[Music]
right funny
whoa just go for the ominous pulsing
penny that scares airport security a lot
more from be an improvement and improved
Modi made a $10 job
I'm Tim Boetsch you got ripped off ten
boxes go to bonus cat righty
brilliant we're about to replace that
that did not have a happy ending
I have no idea who put that up
I like they're obviously paying for
advertising at the eevblog event
batteries I end the water seer and we've
seen some solar freaking roadways and I
think we're going to see some you be
Mary
Meredith Perry goodness apparently I've
heard that they really want to advertise
here they just can't get enough they
want their key audience oh he's
recording me no no I think it's time to
draw the scope that looks totally legit
we're only joined the sponsor of
tonight's event no they got that data
from someone in poster on the ev1 forum
and then they went oh this actually
this looks good we're gonna put it up
do I know who should stop me the Sahara
orchids sell a thousand ideas but I
could never live with myself I tell ya
he's got a shot spawn of these
electronics our particle accelerator
it's a forward and you got a dry yeah
correct
so check out awesome tech is our website
and it's a great story behind how it
came about but what this is is just a
build-it-yourself kit for our desktop
particle accelerator so you've got the
teflon tube and infrared photo gates
there that was true to an Arduino good
old jelly bean you know Arduino and that
will control the timing for the
electromagnet and then the the throttle
here I power me up will will change the
parameters in the software so it's not
just giving it more power no it's more
subtle than that right
atmospheric check the pressure in the
puppy that padam excited about right now
is I'm with a lot of work and I mean you
know piles and piles of versions I
finally got the geometries right in this
CNC milled acrylic here such that the
ball comes in and you know usually it'll
it'll be following the outside track but
with this custom contoured electromagnet
which puts a magnetic field along here I
can now switch the ball onto this inside
track and then eject it out eject it out
just like a beam you know regular
particles correct that is brilliant but
the program make this work recharging
the electromagnets is try to leave a
little magnet I'm a surfer motor yeah so
tried 101 things but I've got kids
that'll be doing correct yeah yeah kid
awesome we'll look at further on
kickstart
okay thanks ladies my Kickstarter or
IndieGoGo at a big Kickstarter but not
yet but if you sign up on awesome check
the website then I'll be able to notify
you when the starter begins sweet thank
you okay
that we here with our stay and he's
gonna show us so this is it's meant to
be a basically a radio telescope for 2.4
gigahertz Wi-Fi signals in terms of
conceptually it's quite simple it takes
in the signal it down converts it
amplifies and then samples it
what could possibly go wrong
yeah so the radio frequency board I
actually had the pleasure of testing
this on the $400,000 spectrum analyzer
at uni know that works the FPGA works in
software
sorry in the simulator this little
amplifying converting board in the
middle is subject to ground pad so
during reflow issues every time the
amplifiers on there's a short every time
it's off it works fine so minor issue
you need the amplifier to make it work
but conceptually it's meant to work
what family 100 megahertz from 2.5 to
3.5 so this is a quad channel ADC 250
mega samples per channel or you know if
I can't get program it does one gig on
one channel yes maybe even more copper
tape for the thermocouple so right my
money port I'm rich so there's a lot of
setting with it and babysitting the oven
[Music]